He's up past his bedtime in the city that never sleeps.
Home Alone 2: Lost in New York is a comedy, family,
adventure film directed by Chris Columbus.
Instead of flying to Florida with his folks, Kevin ends up alone in New York, where he gets a hotel
room with his dad's credit card—despite problems from a clerk and meddling bellboy.
But when Kevin runs into his old nemeses, the Wet Bandits, he's determined
to foil their plans to rob a toy store on Christmas Eve.
Kevin, played by Macaulay Culkin.
Harry, played by Joe Pesci.
Marv, played by Daniel Stern.
Kate, played by Catherine O'Hara.
Peter, played by John Heard.
Pigeon Lady, played by Brenda Fricker.
Home Alone 2: Lost in New York is a 1992 American Christmas comedy film
directed by Chris Columbus and written and produced by John Hughes.
The sequel to Home Alone (1990) and the second installment in the Home Alone franchise, the film stars Macaulay
Culkin, Joe Pesci, Daniel Stern, John Heard, Tim Curry, Brenda Fricker and Catherine O'Hara.
The story follows Kevin McCallister as he is separated from his family on
their vacation to Miami, Florida and ends up in New York City.
While initially enjoying his newfound experiences, Kevin soon encounters
the Wet Bandits again after their escape from prison.
Hughes finished writing the film by February 1991, after
signing a six-picture deal with 20th Century Fox.
Culkin's return was confirmed in May and the rest of
the cast was finalized soon after.
Principal photography took place between December 1991 and May 1992 on location in Illinois and
New York, including at the Rockefeller Center and the original World Trade Center.
Home Alone 2 was theatrically released in the United States
by 20th Century Fox on November 20, 1992.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
However, Home Alone 2 grossed over $359 million worldwide; it
became the third-highest-grossing film of 1992.
Home Alone 2 is the only Home Alone sequel to feature the
majority of the cast from the first film.
Home Alone 3 (1997) featured a new cast and characters, and the television film Home Alone 4
(2002) recast returning characters from the first two films to new actors.
The film explores themes of new york city, burglar,
holiday, family relationships, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.